

M. ENES KAYA

Software Engineer

- enes.kaya95@hotmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-enes-kaya/
- **(** +90 (531) 887 52 67
- https://github.com/eneskaya96

I am a software engineer with a diverse background encompassing more than 6 years of experience in both embedded software/Linux application development and web development. My expertise ranges from full stack and embedded systems development in the defense industry to playing significant roles in startup environments. I excel in backend development using Python, Flask for RESTful APIs, and have a robust understanding of micro service architectures, database management, and cloud platforms like AWS. Additionally, I've contributed to data engineering, handling large-scale data processes with technologies like Airflow, AWS Lambda, and Amazon Redshift.

My proficiency extends to embedded systems, where I've worked with C++11 on Real-Time Operating Systems (RTOS) for surveillance systems, and developed GUI applications using Qt. I've also embraced mobile development in my spare time, creating applications on Android and iOS with Java, Swift, React Native, and Flutter. This journey reflects my dedication to continuous learning and contributing to groundbreaking projects across a spectrum of technologies.

Experience

Trendyol / Full-Time Backend Developer

Aug 2024 - Present Ankara , Turkey

Seller Payment

Java, Go, Kafka, Debezium, PostgreSQL, Kubernetes, Docker ,Elastic Search, Grafana

Crea Inc. / Full-Time Software Engineer - Remote

Feb 2021 - Aug 2024 San Francisco , USA

Twitter Agent (Team Lead)

Python, Flask, MongoDB, Open AI, Appsmith

• Cloud Compass (Frontend Developer)

React.js, Open Al Wrapper, Auth0

Tester App (Mobile Developer)

React Native, Appsflyer, Firebase, AdJoe

• Flexdue (Frontend Developer)

React.js, Angular

• Lemin Captcha (Full Stack Developer)

Python, Flask, Restful API, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, MySQL, CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker, AWS EC2, AWS ElasticBeanstalk, Graylog, Grafana, ETL, Object Oriented Design, System Architecture, Shopify App Extensions

• Joe The Juice (Backend Developer)

Python, Flask, Restful API, AWS Lambda, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Postgres SQL, Redshift, CI/CD, AWS Fargate, AWS ECS, Airflow, Pandas, ETL, Object Oriented Design, Agile, System Architecture, Design Patterns

Mobile Action Ad Intelligence (Full Stack Developer)

Python, Flask, Restful API, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, MySQL, CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker, AWS EC2, Graylog, Grafana, ETL, Object Oriented Design, Agile, System Architecture, Design Patterns

Egemen Tech. / Co-founder

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022 *Ankara , Turkey*

- Software System Design
- Python Web Backend
- Mobile Application Design

Python, Software Design, System Architecture, React Native, Java, Flutter, Websocket

Ankara , Turkey

- Embedded software development for imaging gimbal systems with C++11 in a Linux environment.
- Testing embedded software with debugging tools.
- Simulator/GUI software development with Qt (C++11).
- Scripting, documenting, maintaining, and conducting research.

Python, CI/CD, SQL(MySQL), C++11, C#, Unix Commands, Git, Jenkins, OpenCV, Matlab, Qt, Object Oriented Design, UML, Design Patterns

Aselsan AŞ. / Part-Time Software Engineer - Internship

Jun 2018 - Jun 2019

Ankara , Turkey

• Embedded software development for imaging gimbal systems with C++11 in a Linux environment. Python, CI/CD, SQL(MySQL), C++11, C#, Linux Commands, Git, OpenCV, Matlab, Qt

Desistek Robotics / Internship

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

Ankara , Turkey

• Software system design

C++11

Attent.ai / Internship

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017 San Francisco , USA

- Web developer
- Chrome extensions

JavaScript

Education

Bilkent University 2014 - 2019

Bachelor Degree / Engineering Department / Electronic Electrical Engineering

- GPA: 3.09 / 4.00
- University Placement Exam: 133rd over 2M participants

Language Skills

English Advance Turkish Native

Personal Website

Personal Website

https://www.asendesignandtechnology.com/